webhostingbuzz.com 2018-08-31

# Privacy Policy - WebHostingBuzz

We respect your privacy and are committed to protecting your personal data. This privacy policy will inform you as to how we collect, process and look after your personal data when you visit our Website and tell you about your privacy rights and how the law protects you. The policy is written with special respect to new European personal data protection legislation (GDPR). We are an U.S., company, but we have EU clients, so we are also required to be GDPR compliant, and we also believe that our entire client base would benefit from personal data protection requirements GDPR enables.

 **General information.**

Who we are?  
We are WebHostingBuzz Inc, we maintain our main office at:

56 Leonard St  
Suite 21A-East  
New York, NY 10013  
USA  
Fax: +1-508-597-8354  
Email: management@webhostingbuzz.com

WebHostingBuzz is owned by Cloud Equity Group, located in New York, USA.

 **WebHostingBuzz roles.**

WebHostingBuzz acts as **Data Processor** for any data, that has been uploaded to, sent to, provided to or exchanged with our servers and infrastructure.  
WebHostingBuzz clients remain the Data Controller for all and any data, transferred in this manner.

WebHostingBuzz acts as **Data Controller** only for information, provided to WebHostingBuzz by means of service subscription and as a part of general account management procedures. This includes essential information for the services provided and optional marketing data.

In the Data Controller role, WebHostingBuzz gathers and keeps track of:

Information that users provide through optional, voluntary submissions. These are voluntary submissions made by You in order to receive our electronic newsletters, to participate in our message boards or forums, to email a friend, and from participation in polls and surveys.  
Information WebHostingBuzz gathers through aggregated tracking information derived mainly by tallying page views throughout our sites. This information allows us to better tailor our content to readers’ needs and to help our advertisers and sponsors better understand the demographics of our audience. Because WebHostingBuzz derives its revenue mainly from sponsorships and advertising, providing such aggregated demographic data is essential to keeping our service free to users. Under no circumstances does WebHostingBuzz divulge any information about an individual user to a third party, unless this is explicitly required by the Law.

WebHostingBuzz gathers information about its users as follows:

OPTIONAL VOLUNTARY INFORMATION SUBMISSION

WebHostingBuzz offers the following free services, which require some type of voluntary submission of personal information by users:

Electronic newsletters (Dispatches)  
WebHostingBuzz offers a free electronic newsletter to users. WebHostingBuzz gathers the email addresses of users who voluntarily subscribe to this service. At any time, users are free to remove themselves from this mailing list by following the link provided in every newsletter pointing the user to the subscription management page.

Message Boards/Forums  
Users of the WebHostingBuzz’s Message Boards and Forums must register separately for these services (both are free of charge) in order to post messages. Registration is not required in order to visit or otherwise use WebHostingBuzz’s other services and/or products. However, in order to register for WebHostingBuzz’s Message Boards and Forums, users are required to supply a user name, password, and email address.

“E-mail this to a friend” Service  
WebHostingBuzz users can choose to electronically forward a link, page, or documents to someone else by clicking on “e-mail this to a friend”. In order to do so, the user must provide his email address, as well as the email address of the intended recipient. This information is used only in the case of transmission errors and, of course, to let the recipient know the identity of the sender. The information collected is not used for any other purpose.

Polling  
WebHostingBuzz occasionally offers interactive polls to users in order to enable the users to share their experience with other users as well as to improve WebHostingBuzz’s services. The collected information, including user opinions, testimony and other submitted information is aggregated. This information is not identifiable to any particular user. However, WebHostingBuzz may employ action “tags” (also known as single pixel gifs or web beacons) to tag users after they have voted, in order to prevent the same user from voting multiple times on the same issue. This “tag” is not correlated with the subject user’s individual information.

Surveys  
WebHostingBuzz may occasionally conduct user surveys to better target our content to our audience. We sometimes share the aggregated demographic information in these surveys with our sponsors, advertisers and partners. However, in doing so, we will never share specific user information with any third party.

CHILDREN

Consistent with the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 (“COPPA”), we will never knowingly request personally identifiable information from anyone under the age of 13 without first requesting parental consent.

USAGE TRACKING

WebHostingBuzz tracks user traffic patterns throughout its various sites. However, we do not correlate this information with specific data about individual users. WebHostingBuzz does break down overall usage statistics according to a user’s domain name, browser type, and Multipurpose Internet Mail Extension (“MIME”) type by gathering such information from the browser string (information contained in every user’s browser).

WebHostingBuzz sometimes tracks and catalogs the search terms entered by users in our Search function. However, this tracking is never associated with individual users. We use tracking information to determine which areas of our sites users like and don’t like based on traffic to those areas. We do not track what individual users read, but rather how well each page performs overall. This helps us continue to improve our services for our users.

COOKIES

We may place a text file called a “cookie” in the browser files of your computer. The cookie itself does not contain personal information, although it will enable us to relate your use of this site to information that you have specifically and knowingly provided. The only personal information a cookie can contain is information supplied by the user. A cookie cannot read data from the user’s hard disk or read cookie files created by other sites. WebHostingBuzz uses cookies to track user traffic patterns (as described above).

Our advertising system delivers a one-time cookie to improve tracking of advertisement impressions and click rates.

You can refuse cookies by turning the cookie function off in your browser. If your browser is set to provide a warning before the cookie is accepted, you will receive the warning message with each cookie. You do not need to have cookies turned on to use WebHostingBuzz’s site. However, you will need to enable/accept cookies if you wish to actively participate in our message boards, forums, polling and surveys.

USE OF INFORMATION

WebHostingBuzz uses information voluntarily submitted by our users to enhance the user experience in our network of sites, whether by providing interactive or personalized elements on the sites or by improving future content in response to the interests of our users.

As stated above, we use information that users voluntarily provide in order to send out electronic newsletters and to enable users to participate in polls, surveys, message boards, and forums. We send out newsletters to subscribers on a regularly set schedule corresponding with the frequency of the particular publication, and occasionally send out special editions when we think subscribers might be particularly interested in something we are doing. WebHostingBuzz never shares newsletter mailing lists with any third parties, including advertisers, sponsors or partners.

We use tracking information to determine which areas of our sites users like and don’t like based on traffic to those areas. We do not track what individual users read, but rather how well each page performs overall. This helps us continue to build a better service for you. We track search terms entered in Search function as one of many measures of what interests our users. But we don’t track which terms a particular user enters.

WebHostingBuzz creates aggregate reports on user demographics and traffic patterns for advertisers, sponsors and partners. This enables our advertisers to advertise more effectively, and allows our users to receive advertisements that are tailored to their needs. Because we don’t track the usage patterns of individual users, an advertiser or sponsor will never know which particular user clicked their advertisement.

SHARING OF THE INFORMATION

WebHostingBuzz uses the above-described information to tailor our content to suit your needs and help our advertisers better understand its audience’s demographics. This is essential to keeping our select services free. We will not share information about individual users with any third party, except in order to comply with applicable Law or valid legal process or to protect the personal safety of our users or the public.

 **Data location and security.**

WebHostingBuzz operates two datacenters in the United States. Datacenter in Chicago, IL is used in the Data Processor role, Datacenter in Buffalo, NY is used in both the Data Processor and the Data Controller role. Chicago, IL facility is Type II AT-101 SOC 2 audited yearly, Buffalo, NY facility is SSAE 16 certified.

 **Notice of Breach.**

In the unlikely event of a data breach, we will notify you within 48 hours or 2 business days of us becoming aware to the event.

 **Data retention.**

Where we act as the Data Controller, such as the information held to enable your subscription, we hold this data actively only during your subscription period. Upon cancellation of subscriptions, or services rendered by WebHostingBuzz, we will hold your data for a maximum of a further 365 days. This data is limited to name, address, email address and phone number. Any technical information, that may contain personal data, such as access logs, is stored on our services for no longer than 30 days and deleted automatically. You may request we remove your data before the 365 day period by emailing a request to privacy@webhostingbuzz.com. We will receive, process and respond to your request within 7 (seven) working days.

Where we act as the Data Processor, you, as the WebHostingBuzz client, are responsible for the deletion of data as the Data Controller for any data hosted on our services.  
Any information you delete, modify or change is done so immediately on our servers.  
Whereby we provide additional backups, this data is held for a maximum of 30 days

 **Your Consent and Request for Data Held.**

We give users options wherever necessary. Such choices include:  
The option to not register to receive our electronic newsletters;  
The option to opt-out from our electronic newsletters;  
The option to not participate in certain interactive areas, which completely obviates our need to gather any personally identifiable information from our users.

By using webHostingBuzz site and confirming personal data collection and cookie use, you consent to the collection and use of personal information by WebHostingBuzz. If we decide to change our Privacy Policy, we will post those changes on this page so that you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances we disclose it.

Should you wish to request a copy of the data we hold for you, please email privacy@webhostingbuzz.com with full details of your request. We will receive, process and respond to your request with 7 (seven) working days.

 **Contact us.**

If you have questions or concerns regarding this policy, you can contact WebHostingBuzz Privacy Officer at privacy@webhostingbuzz.com. You can also write to us at the following address:

WebHostingBuzz  
56 Leonard St  
Suite 21A-East  
New York, NY 10013  
USA  
Fax: +1-508-597-8354  
Email: privacy@webhostingbuzz.com
